Okay, this is just a friendly reminder
um that HTML tags when you query them
are returned as objects and that means
they have attributes and you can access
those attributes. So this object this
template tag has a content attribute and
we can use that content attribute to
create cards based on that template. So
coming over here, um let's go ahead and
make this add item function. So we're
going to do function add item.
And the first thing we want to do is we
want to get the template tag. So let's
say let templates equal
document.query selector and we're going
to look for the template tag. Once we
have our template tag, we want to access
the content. If we want to access the
content and we want to use it on the
page, remember template tags are read
only. So if we want to access the
content, we need to import it so that we
can uh make a copy of it and edit that
copy which we can then put on the
screen. So to do that, we'll say let's
new card equal document dot import node.
And it says, well, what node do you want
to import? Well, we want to go to the
template and access its content. The
template content contains all of this
HTML. So if we want to access this HTML,
we need to go to template.content. And
we're going to say take that HTML and
import it here. So now this new card is
that imported content. There are two
ways to import. There are deep imports
and there are shallow imports. Um, and
so if you do a shallow import, all it
will grab is this div. It won't grab
anything inside the div, just the div.
If you want everything inside of the div
like the image tag and the other divs,
then you need to access them. So here in
the import node, it asks if you want to
grab all of the children. So you can put
true if you want all of them, or if you
just want the upper div, then you'll
just put false here. Okay, now that I
have it, I can go ahead and I can query
this new HTML element and I can make
some changes to it. So rather than
having it hardcoded to have this source
and to have this alt and to have this
name and to have this bio, I could
actually um query it. And I took the
liberty of writing this ahead of time so
that you didn't have to watch me write
it. But basically, I'm going into each
of those inputs and I'm grabbing the
files and I'm setting inside of this new
card. I'm setting the image to what I
want, the alt to what I want, the name
to what I want, and the title to what I
want.
Once I'm done with that, I just need to
append it to the page. So, we can say
document.query
selector and we can look for output and
we can append
this new child and it is this new card.
So, if we save this and we come over
here, we can add fluffy
um title cutest
fun.
And we'll upload a picture of Fluffy.
And we'll say open. And we'll add dog.
And there's Fluffy. And he's a fun dog.
And we were able to add a whole bunch of
HTML elements to the page and edit them
without having to create a whole bunch
of elements in our JavaScript code. And
that's the power of templates because
now we can take this and we can name it
um phto
and we can super
energetic
can't spell but you get the picture and
I'll put in dog picture one and I'll add
the dog and now he's on the screen and
now we have a bunch of neat cards added
to the screen and we're able to use a
template and have everything pre-estyled
ahead of